# Lucas Fern

Lifeguard, Coding Instructor, and Student at the University of Melbourne



East St Kilda, 3183, Australia



(+61) 0431 621 232



lucaslfern@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/lucas-fern



github.com/lucas-fern

### Skills

- Planning
- Problem Solving
- Leadership
- Public Speaking
- Programming
  - Python
- o HTML
- o Java
- o CSS/Sass
- o R
- o MATLAB
- Mathematics
  - Statistics
  - o Probability

# Certifications

Working with Children Check (Valid to 26/02/2024)

#### HLTAID003

Provide First Aid (06/2018-06/2021)

#### HLTAID007

Provide advanced resuscitation (06/2018-06/2021)

#### PUAOPE0100C

Operate an AED in an emergency (06/2018-06/2021)

# **PROFILE**

An independent and self-motivated student with strong academic performance; studying Data Science at the University of Melbourne. Proficient at programming in a diverse range of languages.

Proven record of strong communication, public-speaking, and leadership skills from my significant background in teaching and customer service.

Over 8 years of combined volunteering experience with Surf Lifesaving Australia and the University of Melbourne.

Enthusiastic about continuously developing my skills.

# **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Science – Data Science 01/2019 – Present The University of Melbourne Weighted Average Mark: 85.29

My studies in this course have been focused heavily on a combination of Statistics and Computer Science, from which I have developed strong critical thinking and problem-solving skills and a powerful work ethic. Outside of the domain of Science I have pursued an interest in Economics and Business Management, which reflects in my ability to manage and participate in teams in the workplace.

High School Albert Park College ATAR: 95.25 02/2013 - 10/2018

# WORK EXPERIENCE

Programming / Robotics Instructor 12/2020 - Present Junior Engineers

Junior Engineers delivers educational programs in coding and robotics for kids aged 7-15. As an instructor I run holiday and weekly after school programs at Brighton and Elwood Primary schools. In these sessions I teach introductory Python, JavaScript, and general programming skills using tools such as Minecraft Education edition and its integrated code execution capabilities.

This role has made it clear to me how important improvisation and adaptability are in the workplace, especially in teaching. Through working with many schools around Melbourne I have developed my own energetic teaching style and continue to refine my ability to engage students and further their passion for coding and robotics.

# WORK EXPERIENCE (continued)

Lifeguard 10/2017 - Present

# Melbourne Sports and Aquatic Centre

In this role I:

- Developed strong professional communication skills with both colleagues and patrons, especially with conflict management in high-pressure situations,
- Gained abundant practice working with and managing large groups of lifeguards during Australia's largest swimming events,
- Refined my ability for public speaking through a considerable amount of front facing customer service experience.

Mathematics Tutor 2018 – 2019

During this period, I was consistently employed by multiple families at my high school to teach VCE Maths Methods content to senior year students. I was formally recognised in my graduating year for my ability to teach in an engaging and productive way.

# **VOLUNTEERING EXPERIENCE**

Lifesaver 09/2012 - Present

# Port Melbourne / Anglesea Life Saving Club

Since I began at the start of High School, I have completed over 400 hours of volunteer work with Life Saving Victoria, comprised mostly of beach patrols as well as substantial First Aid and rescue training at Port Melbourne, St Kilda, and Anglesea Life Saving Clubs.

I am trained in basic First Aid as well as Advanced Resuscitation, Operation of a Defibrillator, and a range of specific qualifications such as an ability to perform aquatic rescues from a rescue boat.

This has been exceptional experience in effectively managing stressful situations and has taught me how to appear professional when communicating with members of the public, but above all has been rewarding to give back to my local community.

# Science Student Ambassador

01/2020 - Present

# The University of Melbourne

As a student ambassador I have worked closely with the Faculty of Science to assist in delivering a range of events for current and prospective students. In 2020 this has been largely online, where I have been a panellist on webinars for events such as the university Open Day, and a Computer Science exhibition for graduating high school students in India.

In exchange for my volunteering the faculty provides professional development sessions which I have participated in, specifically to further my Public Speaking and Leadership skills.

Peer Mentor Semester 1 – 2, 2020

# The University of Melbourne

In 2020 I participated as a Mentor in the University's peer mentoring program; the role involved sharing my knowledge about the university experience with a group of new students in my course. I was required to be adaptable and fast thinking when running my sessions as the COVID-19 pandemic completely changed the advice I would usually think to provide a mentee about the Bachelor of Science.

# REFEREES

Available on request.